[music]
[音乐]
Hello and welcome to section
您好，欢迎来到本节
four of lesson 3.
第三课的第四课
In this section we're going to be talking about how to use collectors
在本节中，我们将讨论如何使用收集器
as terminal operations on a stream. If we look at the
作为流上的终端操作。如果我们看一下
basics of the collector, what a collector actually does
收集器的基础知识，收集器的实际功能
is to perform a mutable reduction on a stream. So that means it takes the
对流执行可变还原。因此，这意味着需要
elements of the input stream
输入流的元素
and puts them into some kind of container,
并将它们放入某种容器中
which stores the results. What this container can be
存储结果。这个容器可以是什么
is anything that we can actually change. And by that I mean
是我们实际上可以更改的任何东西。我的意思是
things like collections, so we can have a list, we can have a map and we can
像收藏这样的东西，所以我们可以有一个列表，我们可以有一个地图，我们可以
add elements to that. But we can just as easily use
添加元素。但是我们可以轻松地使用
something like a string, where we can concatenate data together
诸如字符串之类的东西，我们可以将数据连接在一起
to form a single result. In terms of using
形成一个单一的结果。在使用方面
the collections what we do is we use the collect
收集我们做的是使用收集
method to terminate stream. We pass a
终止流的方法。我们通过了
collector to the collect method to determine how things are going to be
收集器确定收集方法，以确定情况如何
collected.
集。
What you find is that in the Collectors (with an
您会发现在收藏家中（带有一个
s) utility class there are a number of methods
s）实用程序类有很多方法
that can be used to create collectors. And there's lots of different examples
可以用来创建收集器。还有很多不同的例子
that, which we're going to talk about in the rest of this part of the
那，我们将在本部分的其余部分中讨论
lesson. One of the other things that you can do with collectors is you can actually
课。您可以与收藏家一起做的另一件事是，您实际上可以
compose them,
组成他们，
so you can create more complex collectors from
因此您可以从中创建更复杂的收集器
the basic ones that are available in the Collectors class.
Collectors类中可用的基本的。
There are a number of examples where you can do that.
有许多示例可以做到这一点。
There's the method collectingAndThen,
有方法collectingAndThen，
which allows you to put one collector to after another.
这样您就可以将一个收集器放置到另一个收集器上。
There's the groupingBy or  groupingByConcurrent method
有groupingBy或groupingByConcurrent方法
and we'll see how you can use those with what are called downstream collectors, which is
我们将看到如何将它们与所谓的下游收集器一起使用
a
一种
a second collector to use. Similarly mapping,
使用第二个收集器。类似的映射
where we can describe how we want to apply different collector for generating
在这里我们可以描述我们如何应用不同的收集器来生成
things when we're actually creating a map
实际创建地图时的事情
and also how we can use a secondary collector when're doing partitioning.
以及在进行分区时如何使用辅助收集器。
but as I said we'll look at these with examples as we go through.
但是正如我说的，我们将通过示例进行介绍。
If you want to collect into a collection
如果您想收藏到收藏中
then there's a number of methods that we can use to do that. The most generic, if you
那么我们可以使用许多方法来做到这一点。最通用的，如果您
like,
喜欢，
is toCollection. What that does is it takes
是toCollection。那是什么需要
a method, takes a parameter for the method which is a supplier
一个方法，该方法的参数是供应商
and the supplier is essentially a factory which will
而供应商实质上是一家工厂
create some form of collection that can be used by toCollection into
创建某种形式的集合，供toCollection使用
collection to collect that collection.
收集以收集该收集。
A rather long way of saying a lot of different collections. So we
说很多不同的收藏集的时间相当长。所以我们
create a collection and then the collector will
创建一个集合，然后收集器将
add the element to the input stream to that collection. In terms of
将元素添加到该集合的输入流中。就......而言
a order it uses what's called encounter order, which basically just means
它使用所谓的遭遇顺序的命令，这基本上意味着
that the elements that are coming from the input stream
来自输入流的元素
will be replaced into the collection in whatever order they are made available.
将按照可用的顺序替换到集合中。
If we want to be a bit more specific in terms
如果我们想更具体一点
of the collection we want to use then
然后我们要使用的集合
there are simpler versions of the methods, we can say to List,
有更简单的方法版本，我们可以对List说，
which will simply gather all the elements of stream into a list.
它将简单地将流的所有元素收集到一个列表中。
We can use toSet, which will add all the elements of the input stream to set.
我们可以使用toSet，它将添加输入流的所有元素进行设置。
The thing about a set is it eliminates the duplicates.
关于集合的事情是它消除了重复项。
That's one thing that will do automatically. We can also collect to a map,
这是将自动执行的一件事。我们也可以收集到地图，
and the way this works is that
它的工作方式是
we provide two different functions. A keyMapper
我们提供两种不同的功能。密钥映射器
and a valueMapper. Essentially what
和一个valueMapper。本质上是什么
this will do is it will allow all the collector
这样做会允许所有收集器
to take the input elements and then use the keyMapper function to determine what
接受输入元素，然后使用keyMapper函数确定
the keys of the map are going to be and then use the
地图的键将成为然后使用
valueMapper function to determine what values
valueMapper函数确定哪些值
associated with each key will be if you want to use just the
如果您只想使用
stream elements on their own, if you don't want to do any specific mapping
如果您不想进行任何特定的映射，则可以自行传输元素
then you can use to function.identity method
那么你可以使用function.identity方法
and that simply is a function that returns the value that's passed to it. It
这只是返回返回传递给它的值的函数。它
doesn't change it.
不会改变它。
We've got a example here where I'm taking a collection of students;
这里有一个例子，我在这里收集学生。
and I create stream source and then I pass that
然后创建流源，然后通过
to collect and I say that the way I want to collect is to use the toMap
收集，我说我想收集的方式是使用toMap
method. The keyMapper is
方法。 keyMapper是
going to use the functions.identity method, which means that we'll be using the
将使用functions.identity方法，这意味着我们将使用
student records as the keys and then the valueMapper
学生记录为键，然后为valueMapper
is a function, which in this case will use the score
是一个函数，在这种情况下将使用分数
of the students. We'll end up with a map of student records
的学生。我们将获得一张学生记录图
and the scores that they got in a particular exam. If we
以及他们在特定考试中获得的分数。要是我们
want to deal with duplicate keys in a map then there's another version
要处理地图中的重复键，那么还有另一个版本
of the toMap method. This one takes the same
toMap方法。这个也一样
first two parameters, the keyMapper and the valueMapper,
前两个参数，keyMapper和valueMapper，
but it also has a binaryOperator, which
但它也有一个binaryOperator，
is a merge function. If we look at
是合并功能。如果我们看
the way that works what we can do
我们可以做的工作方式
is we can say, OK, I've got a collection of people.
可以说，好的，我有很多人。
What I want to do is collect those into a map
我要做的是将这些收集到地图中
and for the keys I'm going to use the address
对于键，我将使用地址
of the particular person that's in the input stream and the value
输入流中特定人的身分和值
will be the name of that person. Obviously,
将是那个人的名字。明显，
I may end up with several people living at same address.
我可能最终有几个人住在同一地址。
If that's the case we'll have duplicate keys, because they'll be the same address,
如果是这种情况，我们将有重复的密钥，因为它们将是相同的地址，
so we then use the merge function,
然后我们使用合并功能，
which is defined by Lambda expression. And in this case
由Lambda表达式定义。在这种情况下
what we are doing is concatenating strings
我们正在做的是串联字符串
and placing a comma between the names of the people,
在人们的名字之间加上逗号
so that we end up with a comma separated value string
这样我们以逗号分隔的值字符串结尾
of the people living at a particular address.
居住在特定地址的人口中。
Another thing that we can do is we can group
我们可以做的另一件事是我们可以分组
results and there are two different forms of the
结果，并且有两种不同形式的
groupingBy method. The first of these takes just a function
groupingBy方法。其中第一个仅需一个功能
as a parameter. The idea here is that it uses the
作为参数。这里的想法是，它使用
function to determine what the keys
函数确定什么键
of the map are going to be and then for each of those keys
的地图将是，然后对于每个键
it will use the elements the input stream
它将使用输入流中的元素
to create list of ones which map to
创建映射到的列表
that particular key. The easiest way to understand that is using an
该特定的密钥。最简单的理解方法是使用
example. what I got here is collection of words,
例。我在这里得到的是文字的集合，
so I create a stream source from that and pass it into groupingBy
所以我从中创建一个流源并将其传递给groupingBy
which will then use the length of those words
然后将使用这些单词的长度
as the keys for the map
作为地图的关键
and each other words that matches that length
以及与该长度匹配的其他单词
will be added to the list which is the
将被添加到列表中
the value associated with that key. There's then a
与该键关联的值。然后有一个
second form of this, which has a second collector,
第二种形式，它有第二个收集器，
and this is one of those examples of how we can compose collectors
这是我们如何组成收藏家的例子之一
and use a downstream collector. In this case,
并使用下游收集器。在这种情况下，
if we look at the example we take our stream of words
如果我们看这个例子，我们会说一些话
and this time we're going to group them by length again,
这次我们将再次按长度分组，
so the keys of the map will be the lengths of the
因此地图的键将是
words, but rather than creating a list
单词，而不是创建列表
of the words which matched that length. What we actually want to do
匹配该长度的单词。我们实际上想做什么
is to create value, which is
是创造价值，这是
how many words in that collection
该集合中有多少个单词
match that length. So we use the counting
匹配该长度。所以我们用计数
method to generate a count of how many words
生成多少字数的方法
will have that length and that will be the value associated with the
将具有该长度，并且将是与
the key in the map.
地图中的键。
If we want to join strings we can do that.
如果我们想加入字符串，我们可以做到。
There's a couple of forms of that. We can use joining on its own,
有几种形式。我们可以单独使用加入，
with no method with no parameters
没有参数就没有方法
and that will simply concatenate the input strings together to form one
这将简单地将输入字符串连接在一起以形成一个
string as a result. we can also use
结果是字符串。我们也可以使用
a delimiter and we can pass that as a string.
一个定界符，我们可以将其作为字符串传递。
A good example there where we can use the Collectors.joining
有一个很好的例子，我们可以在这里使用Collectors.joining
with a comma and that will create a comma separated value list.
用逗号分隔，将创建一个用逗号分隔的值列表。
And if we want to we can even use a more
如果我们愿意，甚至可以使用更多
sophisticated form of that where, in addition to a
复杂的形式，除了
delimiter, we can also provide a prefix and a suffix string
定界符，我们还可以提供前缀和后缀字符串
which will be appended both at the beginning and at the end of the string
它将被附加在字符串的开头和结尾
prefix beginning, suffix at the end , with the delimiter being used
前缀开头，结尾后缀，使用定界符
in between the individual values. There are a range
在各个值之间。有范围
of numeric collectors and
的数字收集器和
what I've done to simplify this particular slide is just to give you the
我为简化此特定幻灯片所做的只是为了给您
integer versions of the collector methods that we can talk about,
我们可以讨论的收集器方法的整数版本，
but there's also versions for both double and long.
但也有双重和长期版本。
The first of those is to give you an average.
首先是给你一个平均值。
This will generate a collector which will use the
这将生成一个收集器，该收集器将使用
function you supply to convert the input stream
您提供的转换输入流的功能
into it set of integer values and then the
进入它的一组整数值，然后
collector that are created will average those results. There's a
创建的收集器将平均这些结果。有个
summarizing collector, we can create that using this method.
汇总收集器，我们可以使用此方法创建收集器。
Again this uses the function that you pass as a parameter
同样，这使用您传递的函数作为参数
to determine how to convert the input stream to
确定如何将输入流转换为
a set of numeric values. The summary that you get is a
一组数值。您得到的摘要是
count of the number elements on the input stream,
输入流中数字元素的数量，
you get a total, so a sum of the values that are created;
您得到的总数是所创建值的总和；
you get the minimum, get the maximum, and get the average all
你得到最小值，得到最大值，然后得到平均值
together.
一起。
There is a the summingInt collector,
有一个summingInt收集器，
which we can generate, again using a function and
我们可以再次使用函数生成
this is really equivalent to having a map followed by a sum.
这实际上等同于在地图上加上总和。
Rather than using a collector operation you could use map
与其使用收集器操作，不如使用地图
using the function to convert into numeric values and then you could sum
使用该函数将其转换为数值，然后可以求和
those numeric values.
这些数值。
This is just a kind of shorthand way of doing that. There's two others: There's maxBy and
这只是一种简便的方法。还有两个：maxBy和
minBy, which use comparators to generate
minBy，使用比较器生成
a collector which will give you the maximum
收藏家将给你最大的收获
or the minimum value of the input stream based on how the comparator works.
或基于比较器工作方式的输入流的最小值。
There are few
很少有
other collectors, ways of creating collectors.
其他收藏家，创建收藏家的方式。
One of those is reducing and it takes a binary operator to
其中之一是归约化，需要二元运算符
explain how the collector going to be created.
解释如何创建收集器。
This is really equivalent to the reduce
这真的等于减少
terminal operation and of course the question is, why would you use this is a collector
终端操作，当然，问题是，您为什么要使用它呢？
rather than using
而不是使用
the reduce operation and essentially this is really if you are using a
减少操作，实际上，如果您使用的是
downstream collector,
下游收集器
so if you are using a secondary collector then you could use this
因此，如果您使用的是辅助收集器，则可以使用它
to determine how you want to do a particular reduction.
以确定您要如何进行特定还原。
There is partioningBy
有分手
and what this will create is a collector
这将创建一个收集器
that will generate a map. The map
这将生成一张地图。地图
has two keys:true and false and then
有两个键：true和false，然后
each of the values is a list of the
每个值都是
values, which match either true or false based on Predicate that you get.
值，根据您获得的谓词匹配true或false。
An example of this is if we took a collection of
例如，如果我们收集了
people and we wanted to partition it
人们，我们想对它进行分区
so that we have two groups based on their gender. You could use a Predicate
这样我们就可以根据性别将其分为两组。您可以使用谓词
to test whether they're male or female and then
测试他们是男性还是女性，然后
the partitioningBy collector would create
partitioningBy收集器将创建
two list: one for true, one for false, depending on
两个列表：一个为true，一个为false，具体取决于
whether they're male or not. 00:12:05,350 --&gt; 00:12:08,570 There is also a mapping function
无论他们是男性还是非男性。 195 00：12：05,350-&gt; 00：12：08,570还有一个映射功能
collector and what this will do is create
收藏家，这将是创造
a new collector which can accept different types of elements
一个可以接受不同类型元素的新收集器
based on the function that you provide.
根据您提供的功能。
Best way of explaining that is using an example, like
最好的解释方式是使用示例，例如
what we have here. What we're doing is we're saying, OK we want to
我们这里有什么。我们在说的是，好吧，我们想
collect based on last names by city,
根据城市的姓氏收集
so we've got a collection of people and we create a stream from that name again.
因此我们收集了一群人，并再次根据该名称创建了一个信息流。
We collect it so that we group those people
我们收集它以便我们将那些人分组
by their city but then what we
由他们的城市，但然后我们
want to do in terms of the actual collection
想做的实际收藏
is create a mapping based on that last name into a set.
是根据该姓氏创建一个映射到集合中。
So you get all the people's last name for a particular
这样您就可以得到某人的所有姓氏
city. To summarise section 4 then,
市。然后总结第4节，
collectors provide us with a very powerful way of
收藏家为我们提供了一种非常强大的方式
gathering the elements of the input stream
收集输入流的元素
when we want to generate some kind of result where we looking,
当我们想在我们寻找的地方产生某种结果时，
not necessarily just for a single result, although
不一定只是为了一个结果，尽管
collectors can be used for that. What we can do is if we want to we can collect
收集器可用于此目的。我们能做的是，如果我们想收集
into collection or we can collect in numerical ways, that we can get averages,
收集，或者我们可以用数字方式收集，可以得出平均值，
we can get sums
我们可以求和
and so on. We can compose collectors,
等等。我们可以组成收藏家，
so that we can build more complex ones from from basic ones
这样我们就可以从基本的基础上构建更复杂的基础
and if you want to then you can create your own collector
如果您愿意，可以创建自己的收藏家
but we haven't had time to explore how to do that in this particular
但是我们没有时间探索如何在这个特定的位置
part of the lesson and that
课程的一部分
is the end of this lesson.
这节课到此结束。